wanderu.com 2018-10-05

# Privacy Policy - Wanderu

Updated May 11, 2018.

Wanderu.com has adopted a set of information management guidelines, which serve as the basis for our customer and advertiser relationships. These guidelines disclose the privacy policies that apply to our websites, mobile applications, email and other types of messaging, as well as social media accounts (“Wanderu Channels”). By using the Wanderu Channels you agree to be bound by the terms of this policy.

These guidelines have been developed with the recognition that Internet technologies are rapidly evolving, and that underlying business models are still not established. Accordingly, guidelines are subject to change. Any such changes will be posted on this page.

Wanderu.com is not responsible for the content or the privacy policies of websites to which it may link.

We recommend you also review our [**Cookie Information**](https://www.wanderu.com/blog/cookie-policy/) which provides more information of hos we use cookies and similar technologies.

**What personal data does Wanderu.com gather and/or track about you?**

**Personal data you provide us:**

Wanderu collects and uses information that you provide us. If you make a reservation through one or more of the Wanderu Channels personal data may be needed to facilitate the reservation. Personal data that may be collected related to a reservation may include your name, the names of one or more people that will be using the travel services reserved and/or the name associated with the billing information used for the reservation, passport or other government identification number, age, birth date, email address, telephone number, carrier reward or account information, credit card information, billing address and travel information. When providing information you ensure that the information you are providing is valid, true, and up to date and complete and that you are authorized to provide such information to Wanderu. If you make a reservation on a Wanderu Channel we may automatically create a Wanderu Account for your use though which you can access My Trips features where we may collect your travel information to maintain your travel reservations.

If you contact our customer support through email, our support platform or social media we will collect information including your contact information, inquiry, feedback or user review.

If you register for an account we will collect your email address, password and your passenger travel information and/or preferences that you provide us. If you select to register or login through a third-party service like Facebook or Google you are permitting us to use and store information related to the account used.

You may provide us with personal information when you perform a reservation, sign up for email notifications or the like. We may also collect device information and settings that may allow us to establish your physical location including location information associated with your IP address, WiFi information, GPS location information and other technologies that allow you search using your location or receive content relevant to your location. Wanderu uses this information to personalize your interaction and content served by Wanderu to offer you an experience and products that are more interesting to you. Wanderu only has access to information that you enable your device to provide to us

**Personal data you provide us about others:**

As part of making a reservation you may provide us with the personal data of another person who is either a passenger on reservation you are making or a person on whose behalf you are performing a reservation on Wanderu. It is your responsibility to ensure that the persons whose information you provide to us is aware that you provided us such information and that they have accepted how Wanderu uses their data per this Privacy Policy.

**Personal data we automatically collect about you:**

When you visit the Wanderu Channels, Wanderu may collect information about your visit including personal information. This may include IP address, screen size, browser and operating system info and settings, and referral information of your visit. We also collect information about your interaction with the Wanderu Channels such as what pages you visit. If your interaction is on a mobile device we may collect mobile device identifying information as well as device location and settings.

**Personal data we receive from other sources:**

Besides the information that you provide us we may also receive information about you from other sources including business partners and other third parties. This information may be combined with the information that you provide us. For example to complete a reservation you may provide information to a payment processor or travel provider and these third parties may share that information with us to facilitate the completion of a reservation.

In addition we might also receive information about you to deliver more relevant content or marketing information. If you link your Wanderu account with a social media provider some of your personal data may be shared with Wanderu by the social media provider, but only if you have granted the social media provider such permission.

_Anonymous Information._

Wanderu Channels may also gather anonymous information, which may be used by Wanderu or shared with third parties. This is information which does not personally identify you, but which may be helpful for marketing purposes or for improving the services we offer, such as Google Analytics. Generally this information is collected through “traffic data” and may entail the use of “cookies,” “IP addresses,” or other numeric codes used to identify a computer.

Wanderu Channels employs cookies to recognize you and your access privileges on the Web site, as well as to track site usage. Subscribers who do not accept cookies from the domain (e.g. “Wanderu.com”) might not be able to access areas of Wanderu Channels. We may use an advertising server developed by a third party, to display ads on our site or ad links to third party websites. Some of these ads may contain cookies that are set by third parties (i.e., advertising agencies or advertising clients). We do not have access to these cookies or any information that they may contain. Acceptance of cookies from domains other than Wanderu.com is optional.

**Why does Wanderu collect and use your personal data?**

Wanderu uses the personal information to provide and improve the offerings and services of the Wanderu Channels, as well as to facilitate your reservation of products on Wanderu, store your travel information for your convenience and display relevant and useful advertising and offerings. More specifically your personal data may be used in one or more of the following ways:

  1. Travel Reservations: We use your personal data to complete and service your online travel reservations.
  2. Customer Service: We work hard to ensure we can answer all of your question and concern. To help with your question we need to be able to provide our customer support your information.
  3. Wanderu Account: On the Wanderu Channels you can create a user account. With the information your provide us we are able to offer the account features. You can set your reservation information to use for future reservations, retrieve your completed reservations, and if the travel provider allows you can retrieve your tickets or cancel your reservation.
  4. Marketing: We use the information you provide for marketing activities including: 
    * Sending news of travel offerings and company updates when you make a reservation with us or if you set up an account. If you would like to unsubscribe from these marketing emails you can just click “Unsubscribe” at the bottom of such emails.
    * We may use your information to provide personalized content offerings on the website to better offer you more relevant content.
    * If you participate in promotion activities with Wanderu like giveaway, sweepstakes and the like we may use your information to administer such activities.
  5. Market and User Research: We may ask some users to participate in surveys or user testing. As part of such activities personal information you provide us for these activities will be used only with your consent.
  6. Fraud Prevention: To make sure only valid transactions occur on the Wanderu Channels we and our travel providers may use your personal data to detect and prevent fraud and other activities that are illegal or in breach of our terms. Personal data may be used for threat assessment and validation of transactions and reservations including the blocking of certain transactions or reservations.
  7. Statistical Analysis for Product Improvement: Wanderu may perform statistical analyses of user behavior in order to measure interest in the various areas of our site (for product development purposes). We make the outmost effort to use anonymized information when performing such analysis. Such analysis is used to improve the Wanderu Channels and serve more relevant content for our users.
  8. User reviews: We may ask you to provide a review of your experience with the Wanderu Channels or your travel experience.
  9. Communication with you: We may from time to time get in touch with you by email, mail or phone based on the contact information you provided us and reasons for the communication. Such reasons for communicating with you include: 
    1. In furtherance of assisting you with a transaction or reservation you made or are trying to make.
    2. If you have not finished a reservation we may contact you to remind you and offer help completing the reservation to ensure that you are successful in fulfilling your travel needs.
    3. We may send information that we believe would help you with your reservation like a reminder of your upcoming travel details.
    4. Administrative and other messages that we believe are necessary for your use of the Wanderu Channels.
  10. Legal purposes: In certain case we might need to use the information that you provide us in furtherance of resolving legal disputes, for regulatory investigation and/or compliance, to enforce the Wanderu reservation terms or to comply with lawful requests from law enforcement.

**What legal basis does Wanderu rely on to processes the data as described?**

Performing a contract: Using the information you provide us may be needed to perform the contract that you have with Wanderu. For example, if you use Wanderu to make a reservation we use the data to process, complete and carry out the reservation obligations under the contract we have with you. For travel reservations and customer support Wanderu relies on performance of a contract to process your information as we would not be able to carry out our contractual obligations without this information.

Legal interests: Using your information may be required for our legitimate interests such as delivering an experience on the Wanderu Channels that is most relevant and useful for you, as well as deliver the appropriate emails and newsletters, as well for user support, fraud protection, legal purposes and to improve and promote Wanderu services. For reasons 3-9 listed above Wanderu relies on legitimate interest to process your data and we always balance your users’ right and interests in protecting your personal data with Wanderu’s rights and interests. For purpose 10 when applicable Wanderu also relies on legal obligation to process your data in case such as lawful law enforcement requests.

For the use of your data for direct marketing we will obtain your consent, if required by applicable law, as a prerequisite to processing your data for such purpose.

**What does Wanderu do with the information it gathers and/or tracks?**

_Email and Other Contact_

Using the email addresses and mobile notifications, Wanderu may use your email or mobile application notifications to send you reservation confirmation, reservation tickets, alerts and notifications that you have asked to be subscribed to, to get in touch with you for customer service or to send you marketing promotions from Wanderu email addresses or Wanderu apps with information about our offerings or those of our partners only if you have opted-in to receive such contact from Wanderu or have made a reservation through Wanderu. Marketing emails and notification have an opt-out and you can unsubscribe from these at any time. Wanderu does not allow you to disable contact emails for transactional, service or administrative emails as those are needed to carry out the Wanderu services.

_With whom does Wanderu share the information it gathers and/or tracks?_

Wanderu may share the information it gathers with third parties for legitimate business purposes as permitted by law such as transmitting your information to a travel service provider so they can issue a reservation or provide you travel services. If you make a reservation through the Wanderu Channels we may share your personal information with the travel providers you are reserving with, the company offering the travel service and/or payment processing providers. Depending on the reservation and the travel provider, the personal information that we may share with the travel provider may include your name, age, birth date, IP address, contact information, payment information, and names of passengers you provide, any special requirements or other information that you provided for your reservation with the travel provider. The travel providers process your personal information as data controllers in accordance to their respective privacy policies. We may additionally share your personal data according to the details provided at the time the information was submitted. If you provide us any comments, feedback or review you authorize us to publish such information individually or in aggregate with other submissions. If your reservation requires customer support or dispute we may provide the travel provider with additional information that is needed by the travel provider to resolve the issue.

Wanderu uses third party service providers to process your personal data for us. This processing is for fraud prevention, sending reservation details and marketing materials. All third party service providers used by Wanderu are bound by confidentiality agreements and are not permitted to use your personal data for any purpose other than instructed by Wanderu.

Wanderu may need to share your personal data with payment providers and other financial institutions in cases of chargebacks we need to share your information about the reservation made with the relevant financial institution to resolve the chargeback and only when we believe the sharing of information is necessary for fraud detection and prevention. This may include your reservation details and the IP address you used to make the reservation.

Wanderu may share aggregate anonymous information related to the use of the Wanderu Channels with other third parties. Wanderu may provide personal information if required by law as a result of court order, subpoenas and other orders as a result of legal proceedings, administrative or criminal investigations. Wanderu may also disclose personal information if it is necessary to enforce our rights and claims, in response to legal actions, or to prevent, detect or in the process of prosecuting a criminal act or prevention of other damage

We may share your personal data with advertising partners including your email address as part of promoting Wanderu services through third party channels to assist us in showing our advertisements to relevant user audiences. We make efforts to minimize the information shared to ensure your personal data won’t be used for any other purposes.

**Wanderu and mobile devices:**

Wanderu offers its services on both mobile apps and a mobile website. We process your personal information the same way on mobile devices as on our desktop websites. Mobile devices do allow you with your permission to access your location which we use to make searching for travel easier and serving more relevant content. With your permission we may send you push notifications with details about your reservations. Your mobile device includes settings that you can use to control your location sharing and push notifications. Wanderu may use cross device tracking to link your use of Wanderu on mobile device and desktop ones to better serve you and optimize your experience. Wanderu accounts allow you the option to create an account and login with your social media account for your ease of use. You can decide to disconnect your social media account from you Wanderu account at a later time. Wanderu also has integrated some social media plugins which allow you to share content on the corresponding social media platforms, in the act of sharing some information is passed to the social media provider to facilitate the content share.

**Wanderu and social media:**

Wanderu uses social media to communicate with our users, provide customer service, promote our services as well as improve and facilitate our product offerings.

**What security and retention procedures does Wanderu use to protect your personal data?**

_ _ To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the appropriate use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to protect the information we collect online.

Wanderu’s servers and data centers are in the United States and the Republic of Ireland. Wanderu’s service providers may be located in these countries or in other countries. By providing Wanderu your personal information you agree that your personal information may be transferred and stored in such countries which may have different or more lax privacy protection, data protection or data security laws. By providing your information to Wanderu your personal information may be subject to data requests from law enforcement, courts or government agencies in such countries according to their applicable laws and regulations. Wanderu will make provisions for proper protection of your personal information. Wanderu implements security measures to protect the transmission and storage of personal information to protect from unauthorized access or use. Wanderu implements Secure Socket Layer (SSL) to protect data in transmission over the internet and stored personal information is protected by security technologies including firewalls, possible encryption and other security measures in line with industry standards. In addition, personal information is restricted to only access and use by Wanderu team members when necessary for them to perform their duties and our authorized third party service providers for the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy.

Wanderu uses a variety of third party service providers as part of providing the Wanderu Channels. These service providers may be located outside or inside the European Economic Area. The service providers may assist Wanderu with fraud prevention, customer service, advertising or payment processing. The providers have access to the information limited to what they require to perform the tasks for us and are contractually required to use the information consistent with our Privacy Policy.

Some Wanderu products incorporate Google Maps API(s) which are covered by [Google Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy) which you agree to by using Wanderu services.

If you navigate to third party websites or platforms, Wanderu’s Privacy Policy no longer applies.

**A Special Note About Children.**

Children are not eligible to use Wanderu Channels’ services, and we ask that minors not submit any personal information to us. If you are a minor, you may use this service only in conjunction with a parent or guardian. Wanderu does not knowingly collect personal information from minors.

**Access to Your Data, Opting-Out, Corrections and Cancellations.**

You have the ability to request with proof of identification and receive a report of all of your personal information that we store in accordance to applicable law without charge unless in rare cases where a charge maybe necessary if the law permits. In some case we may not be able to provide you access to your stored personal data if it contains other sensitive information or if restricted by law, but we will provide you an explanation of the situation.

Upon request, Wanderu will: (a) remove you and your personal information from our database not associated with a reservation; (b) correct personal information that you state is erroneous; or (c) permit you to “opt out” of further email contact (except administrative and transactional emails) while still allowing access to the site. Wanderu will make a best effort to carry out your requests, but legal or other obligations such as mandatory data retention may prevent us from deleting, modifying or anonymizing some information.

To request a correction or cancellation, or any other contact regarding this Privacy Policy please contact us at [privacy@wanderu.com](mailto:privacy@wanderu.com) or Privacy Officer – Wanderu Inc., 125 Broad St, Floor 3, Boston, MA 02110, USA.

**Cookies and other tracking tools.**

Please see our [Cookie Policy](https://www.wanderu.com/blog/cookie-policy/) for more information on how we use cookies and other tracking tools.

**EU-US & Swiss-US Privacy Shield.**

Wanderu complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-US Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States, respectively. Wanderu has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this Privacy Policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more visit the [Privacy Shield website](https://www.privacyshield.gov/) as well as Wanderu’s Privacy Shield certification.

Under the Privacy Shield Framework, Wanderu is subject to the authority of the Federal Trade Commission. For any questions or concerns relating to our Privacy Shield certification, contact Wanderu at Wanderu, Inc., Legal Department, 125 Broad St, Floor 3, Boston, MA 02110 or by email at legal@wanderu.com. If we are not able to resolve your concern, you may also contact your European Data Protection Authority or Commissioner or contact our designated Privacy Shield independent recourse mechanism, [JAMS](https://www.jamsadr.com/). In certain circumstances, you may also have the right to pursue binding arbitration through the Privacy Shield Framework, as described in [Annex I to the Privacy Shield Principles](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction).

In accordance to our Privacy Policy, Wanderu sometimes shares information with third parties to perform services on our behalf. Wanderu continues to be responsible for the information shared under the Privacy Shield with such third parties except where we can establish that Wanderu is not responsible for the violation.
